## **Ethan Vander Horn**

ethan.vanderhorn@gmail.com | San Diego, California

Full-stack XR Unity Developer with 8+ years of experience at a VC-backed Startup building XR Molecular Modeling Software used by thousands of Pharmaceutical Scientists.

Currently seeking a Senior Unity Developer Role either Remote or in San Diego, CA

## Skills

Languages: C#, Go, Python

**Software Development:** Unity, UIToolkit, ReactiveX, VR, CI, Git, OOP, Jira, Kanban, Agile, Coda, OculusSDK, ViveSDK **Technical Communication:** Skilled in conveying complex ideas to technical and non-technical stakeholders, facilitating effective collaboration

## Experience

Nanome Senior Unity Developer (2022-2024) | Unity Developer (2018-2022)

2018-2024

Nanome is a VC-backed startup offering XR molecular modeling software, used by scientists at over half of leading pharmaceutical companies. I played a key role as one of the first ten employees, developing the product from early stages to commercialization and scaling in the cheminformatics industry.

- Rapidly iterated on a Unity application from initial idea phase to revenue generating product
- Worked directly with customers and industry experts, playing a major role in identifying and prioritizing features for the app to meet specific real-world needs and requirements to deliver real user value
- Collaborated with developers, designers, and specialists to create user-focused solutions
- Developed and maintained cross-platform collaboration apps for PC and Standalone VR
- Established advanced P2P networking through Photon for real-time collaboration in a challenging use-case
- Developed a Go server using Amazon Web Services (EC2, S3, RDS) for business logic and persistent data storage
- Early adopter of **Unity's UIToolkit** for both editor and runtime interfaces, overcoming the limitations of its early release stage and ensuring maintainable and scalable user interfaces
- Used **ReactiveX/UniRX** for asynchronous and functional programming, improving code maintainability by reducing side effects and simplifying complex event-driven workflows through declarative data streams.
- Implemented Continuous Integration and Deployment processes using Jenkins and Unity build compilation, incorporating unit tests and automated pipelines to enhance reliability and accelerate development speed
- Applied Clean Architecture principles alongside Dependency Injection and adopted CQRS principles to support
  efficient, data-centric workflows, ensuring modularity and refactorability
- R&D and integration of a 3rd party in-app Web Browser for Android and Windows using **Vuplex** and video-encoding for in-app networked screen sharing
- Performed diverse application optimizations from audio/P2P voice compression using Opus, memory runtime
  management, and profiling-based optimization to enhance application performance in a resource-constrained
  environment (standalone XR devices)
- Created an advanced interactive 3D Playback System for real-time recording of interactions, voice, and commands, featuring playback options like rewinding and fast-forwarding
- Developed a comprehensive Python plugin library, enabling external developers to programmatically access the
  molecular modeling app, integrate proprietary industry tools, and create user-generated menus that embed
  seamlessly into the Nanome interface
- As a sole developer, ideated and built a GUI-based menu-building companion app allowing non programmers to create menus for their plugins that were embeddable to the XR platform
- Mentored interns by managing tasks, providing code support, and offering feedback through code reviews
   Nanome Junior Unity Developer
- Developed Calcflow, open-source software used at UC San Diego to interactively teach high-level mathematics in VR

## Education